Ilyas Kerbal Android Software Engineer

+212 681564731

★ kerbalsc@gmail.com

Morocco

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 6+ years of experience in Android development. Strong engineering professional with a Master's degree focused in Data Science from the School of Information Science (ESI). I have worked on numerous freelance projects and built and published many apps on my own. Self-motivated, flexible, and adaptable; I can adapt to both self-starting and collaborative environments while focusing on high-quality results under strict deadlines.

EXPERIENCE

Android Engineer 07/2020 - 06/2022

BidSys

- Performing the end-to-end integration and testing of software components and deploying them onto hardware through manual and automated test development.
- · Identify and correct bottlenecks and fix bugs.
- Work with the product and design teams to understand end-user requirements and use cases and translate them into pragmatic and effective technical solutions.

Freelance Android Developer

08/2016 - 05/2022

UpWork

- Build quality applications based on product requirements.
- Translate designs and wireframes into high-quality code.
- Provide suggestions on UI Design for a superior user experience based on prior experience.
- Ensure the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of the application.
- · Integrating third-party libraries and APIs
- Building from early stages, shipping through Google Play Store.

(Internship) Mobile Developer

01/2020 - 07/2020

LE DIGIMENTAL LIMITED

Master's degree final project:

- Building and maintaining a Flutter app for hotels' internal management.
- · Android UI design principles, patterns, and best practices.

EDUCATION

Android Kotlin Developer 2022

Udacity - Nanodegree

- Taught by Google Engineers, introducing the latest and best practices for Android development: MVVM architecture, Dependency injection (DI), ViewModel, LiveData, Data Binding, Repository Pattern, Navigation Component, Unit Testing, End-to-End Testing, Jetpack library, and more.
- Worked with more than 19 projects and built 5 on my own.

Data engineering and computer science

2020

School of Information Sciences (ESI) - Master's degree

SKILLS

Jetpack compose MVC, MVP, MVVM, MVI

Clean Architecture Java / Kotlin
Dependency Injection Coroutines

Dagger Hilt Test-driven development

REST APIs Unit Testing

CI/CD Gradle

Google Maps SDK Git / GitFlow

Google Cloud Platform Github
Firebase Bitrise